hello and welcome back to another
hermitcraft episode yeah i'm already up
to something you you know it mumbo is
back from his travels as you can see
mumbo jumbo is now online and i thought
it'd be funny to give him a little
welcome back gift so as you know eggs
are kind of the little thing that i did
right at the start and i thought i
really i haven't annoyed him in a while
he is due to have a meeting with me very
very soon but i thought i'd do this
anyway he hasn't even noticed that i'm
here by the way he's down there walking
around somewhere
and he's not seen me once
so i'm hoping that he'll see this in a
while he'll break it open he won't
really have a choice and all of these
chickens are gonna fly everywhere oh
he's there oh
uh oh
i don't know if he was just flying
around i don't know if he saw me
does he know does he think i'm up to
something because i definitely am up to
something
i can see you building look look at him
go
he's just doing his whole redstone thing
he just flew around
did he seriously miss me i might go grab
some more eggs but i don't know how long
i don't know how long i can get away
with this for i've been wondering what
to do with all these eggs for a really
long time and now that we now we know i
think the beauty of this is we could
have done this weeks ago we could have
done this any time mumbo wasn't on the
server but we decided to do it while
he's there i think that just makes it
all the more sweet as long as i come in
from a high distance he shouldn't see me
fly in he probably isn't looking up this
is so perfect he has no idea
no idea
they're all baby chickens at the moment
but as soon as they're adults this will
be great i think we're re we've reached
capacity this is as much as it gets
because as soon as you add another one
look see if we get one more to spawn
he kind of gets sucked into the vortex
and then he gets entity crammed
yeah you see that
okay i think this is where we're gonna
leave this little escapade
no
no oh that was quick
okay let's just leave it at that because
as soon as i my pickaxe is too fast it's
gonna see all of these blocks coming
down
sandstone was perhaps not a smart way to
do this okay there we go it's the
chicken bomb
he'll know exactly what's in there but i
hope he just i hope he just opens it up
okay we'll leave it for now don't know
where he's gone but hopefully he'll find
that little chicken bomb i doubt oh ow i
doubt that he's going to fall for it but
it should be pretty fun
so i just got back on the hermitcraft
from a weekend away
and someone has decided to jingle my map
in the matrix room so there's writing
all over the walls and mumbo the spoon
that he is has already gone in there
without me being online so he's seen it
so this kind of works out in a weird way
mumbo doesn't get the full effect
meaning i can still meet him today
and well yeah apart from having to fix
this
no harm no foul i hope but this is a bit
annoying i'm not gonna lie but i've
fixed it just about now i just need to
go and grab some snow it's not the end
of the world to fix and all it said was
you have been jingled now i don't know
what that means but it's going to vanish
very quickly because i worked hard on
this matrix room and it's going to stay
exactly the way it was supposed to be
and then hopefully we can meet mumbo in
a second so i need to go and find some
more snow now
look there it is you have been jingled
okay let's fix this up please tell me i
have enough snow for this
oh i
don't have enough snow
oh oh dear okay it looks like it's all
fixed there we go that's the last little
bit that's gone
the match is now complete so we can head
back to the base and i actually got a
load more sand as well i just need to
remember that i've got a little
stockpile here if i ever need it
let's just go back to the base now mumbo
is now officially online so we might be
able to have the meeting that i actually
intended to have in the first place
in theory it should be fixed
perfect this is the real thing that
you're supposed to have so this is the
map that i took to fix it and boom
everything is back to normal so now all
i gotta do is kind of wait for mumbo but
i might go and check up on what he's
doing before i let him know man i'm
getting really good at knowing where
this is just in relation to this you can
pop through here
let's head over to mumbo and see what
he's up to this is a really long
elevator i can't wait to get the
maybe in my meeting i can talk to mumbo
about potentially creating this mob farm
is like a joint venture
why is this black
oh what
that's really weird it's like got
glitched here
uh
what is this
another prank
you gotta be kidding me really
what is this
hold on let's get a good view of this
it's the eye of sauron
that's actually not that far off what i
was gonna make i was gonna make like an
orb up here anyway
[Laughter]
dude i'm probably the villain now
that is mordor
essentially it is the futuristic mordor
of the hermitcraft server
oh my goodness i'm afraid that
when there's a prank i think normally i
would try and keep it if it works with
the base but just like the potted plan i
think this one's going to have to go but
i'm gonna keep it here for a while is
there anything in it is there any signs
who did this to me
is there anything to go on is there
something inside
i'm gonna take lots of damage ow hot
coals hot coals hot coals hot coals
anything
no
oh there is something
now
now that you see everything
thank you
iskall
and a diamond i mean it's worth it for
the diamond am i right this is kind of
messing with my eyes
oh that is so strange i don't really
know what to do with this but wow this
must have taken a really long time kudos
to you iskall now that you see
everything i am always watching how did
he put the diamond there is there a
armor stand
so that's oh i see that's why it's
turned black here so that's why this has
turned black because there's a black
stained glass there and for some reason
it stops
just at this point which makes it
extremely weird looking i thought the
entire beam changes color i would have
maybe noticed something was up otherwise
well i guess i'm going to leave that
there until i'm going to be making my
nether portal because my idea at this at
the start was to make like this
futuristic globe type thing at the top
but i mean that's a pretty good
substitute in the meantime as you can
see i've been working on this final
layer up here
and
it's getting there it just takes a long
time to do
i i'm sorry i can't quite get over this
one that's good that's really good
anyway i'm getting i'm getting
completely distracted
so lots of you pointed out that you can
see my spoiler through the glass here
and i knew that i haven't quite finished
making my spoiler wall there's nothing
there to see yet
and now that the infinity room is now
fixed
it's time there we go mumbo meeting
now
hello mumbo this is the weirdest place
this is seriously weird i know it's kind
of freaking me out a little bit you
should see it without the chairs it's
even worse you just have no point of
reference oh how far away can you go
as far as i want this is the infinity
room no i'm joking you hit a wall
have you managed that this is ridiculous
i know this is really really strange
it's so cool like this is like the
probably the best meeting room
ever
yeah you're definitely focused on what
the other person is saying there's no
distractions there's no kind of looking
out the window i don't know is that was
that like yeah
there's also no escape mumbo yeah yeah
no i can't i can't get away from you
here so um
so i mean what have you brought me here
to discuss i'm interested now right
there's a there's several things that i
want to discuss so right at the start of
the season i talked about doing a bit of
a team up bro ship
yeah and we've not really done anything
yet but i think now that our bases are
sort of coming together it might be time
to sort of team up and do a few projects
together
yeah no no for sure architect is
architect is coming i guess we're
full steam ahead we are we are ready to
go
i don't know where to look other than i
mean i'm feeling like you know when you
look into someone's eyes for too long
you start to think maybe there's no way
there's nowhere to learn
nowhere else to look around there's
nothing to be distracted by what sort of
projects do you have in mind i mean the
first one is the elevator i
followed the map i downloaded it i broke
it instantly accidentally nice um but
then i realized that the elevator you
made was a lot shorter than the one that
i've made and right i'm struggling to
get the pulse just right
so okay use a hand on that
and then yeah yeah no there's a there's
a little secret project that i'm working
on on the second floor of my base and
it's a secret to everyone except me and
you it's gonna be i i need help making
it cause i don't have the technical
expertise but it is a pure secret no one
will see it until it is the day it is
finished are you in right
i mean i yeah i'm all for secret
projects and things and and that sounds
like something that i would definitely
be up to is it so you need redstone
expertise yeah you need the tech side of
architect yeah
and a little bit of magic in there as
well
okay
right okay
now architect we need to add like a
wizard to the end of it or something so
the other thing i was thinking is i can
help you with any building needs that
you have and
have you got a mob farm yet
i actually don't i that's something i
normally build really early in the
season um but no i haven't even touched
a mob farm yet which is it's definitely
a project that's kind of on the horizon
well i was wondering maybe it won't be
the most efficient but
maybe what we should do is take a tour
of each other's bases and go over some
of our plans and then we can kind of
work out who can help with what
that is that sounds like a good move
that sounds like a great idea brilliant
how do we get out of here you don't i
mean like
you don't know there's a little there's
a little secret door
but without i tell you what without
these chairs you would never find it
it's right here
that's so creepy to go through there
like to watch you kind of merge through
wait being in here on my own is even
weirder
it this is yeah
don't do that
hold on can i get it can i get it just
so that my head my face is out just my
face
oh you've even gone you've
even a void elevator yep
you know hermitcraft hermitcraft season
seven this is going to be my like my
entire base is just going to have no
no perspective whatsoever you just don't
know where anything is environment
i was actually thinking at some point if
i ever have enough time you could make a
labyrinth out of that like imagine you
have multiple multiple hallways and you
don't know where any of the doors are
you'd have a proper 3d completely
sensory deprived room yeah oh my word
you'd definitely start you should you
could even mix in like some
hallucinations that just come across
because once you start once you start
going crazy start just losing your
marbles
oh man
well at least at least this is this is a
little bit prettier i suppose yeah in a
way
there's actually something to look at
here so yeah i guess i'll start off with
a tour of my base and then we could go
over to yours
all right well should we pop on over to
mine so that i can i can give you a full
a full tour yes so you can see exactly
what's going on
i mean
it's i you know i always i feel a little
bit bad because mine
almost and this is not something i would
say often because my base is also pretty
massive yeah but it actually doesn't
feel as grand as yours at this point in
time i feel like i need to step up my
game and expand mine mine now wow looks
like the short and fat one
you're the
mine is the short and fat one but it
looks like yeah so it's very globular
that's what i'll say
yeah it is and you know what i mean i
never realized how squashed so it looks
a tiny bit squashed because obviously we
the
if i wanted it to be a perfect sphere it
would have the this circle here also on
the corners
but you do remember i didn't really want
to do that do you remember me saying
when you built this that it looks a bit
squashed and you and your response to me
was no it's not
well see here's the thing
so i from your base from your base it
actually does look a little bit squashed
from any other angle you've got like the
it's like it's like you've got like the
side on like if you look at someone's
face from directly to the side they can
be really attractive but some people
just have a weird side on side on look
like
you're saying that your base has a good
side
yeah my base has got a good side but if
you if you look at it from above like if
you fly out and maybe get some height on
you
then it can look it looks pretty fancy
because you can look down and see all of
the all of the biomes up at the top yep
and then you can see all of the storage
systems if you go sort of halfway and
look at it side on yeah you can see that
it has a little bit
it's a few blocks short of being a
being a football that's that's
it's a little bit of an egg this is like
my storage system area um so this is
this is what i've i've got filled well
in the process of filling out so these
are my storage silos which are going to
be for all of the sand gravel
cobblestone stone all that sort of thing
so all of these chests are gradually
going to fill up throughout the season
and then as that happens all of the
redstone lamps will turn on
and
obviously all of this is going to be
automated so
this this area here
i'm going to have a chest on top of that
i place items on the inside and then
those items get sent throughout the
entire system so they'll kind of run
along that water stream there and then
they'll make their way down this branch
it goes it goes all the way around
yeah yeah yeah
that's so metal
yeah
where have you gone
in that gap you're so lucky that there's
not loads of mobs there because i always
get killed from those guys both of our
bases are just
totally a little bit deadly
yeah
oh okay i think i do understand so you
just chuck items in yeah it puts it
round until it finds the right hopper
with the right amount of like yeah like
that in
yeah and then it will allow it to drop
through so then it drops through that
that's what this is what's the redstone
for why not just have it drop through
well because here's the thing so you
have to make sure the way that this i
will try my best to explain this so yeah
so that there is now stopped right so
you can see that we have all the items
in and then we have 41 at the front so
the redstone's to stop it
yeah so so essentially this redstone
here so you can see that it is powering
out to two blocks yeah and then when
another item comes through
it will then extend that redstone signal
out to three to three blocks so that
means that this redstone gets powered
then this repeater gets powered and this
redstone torch unpowers allowing that
item to drop through that hopper okay
and then go through into the system that
makes a lot of actually makes sense
so explain this you spent a long time
making this glass dome underneath and i
was under the impression that this would
become an aquarium of some kind yeah
yeah that i mean i'm still tempted to
make the aquarium i kind of want i i
wouldn't mind getting your ideas on this
because do you think it should be an
aquarium or do you think it should
literally just stay as like a gigantic
sphere area or it could become like the
new death games area where we have
dogfights and things which would be
quite interesting especially with these
tridents as well in fact the tridents
make things exciting because then you
only have one shot so it's kind of like
you fly around and they're not both
you can throw tridents under water
that's true oh that's such a genius idea
this would actually be a lot of fun
to goof around and just mess around with
the hermits especially you okay here's
here's the idea here's here's the pitch
so
what if this is an aquarium it's all
underwater with some decorations and
stuff but yeah yeah we get depth strider
on everyone's boots plus we make some
dolphin uh booster points thank you
we put some dolphin booster points and
you can swim really fast so you have a
trident war zone where everyone is
swimming at this faster than you can fly
yeah yeah
oh that's a good move and it doesn't
cost a million fireworks and yep does it
take damage
yeah oh that would be fun
i don't know how dark it would look
though that's the other the other
question it would but it might be pretty
dark but i think with pickles um i have
a pickles for sale if you need them what
i hadn't realized you could farm them
forget that no i'm farming
you can't farm them that machine was
just a it was just a joke it was just a
show
you see it looks really lovely and
bright at the moment like really bright
and i think you could still get that
with sea pickles it may even look more
majestic if it's like got that blue
tinge it's
i'd say break a few of it on like one
corner or one question
just to do like one quarter but this
death
death dome would look really cool
especially with like the dolphin booster
and deathstrider it would be a really
fun battle
i am really like this is crazy
it's actually really different how we've
both tackled our bases so you've you've
sort of built this around your redstone
first and then yeah i sort of built
something first and then tried to fit
the redstone in so it's the same
principle just reversed
yeah yeah yeah it is interest and it's
interesting to hear how we both have
like no plan yeah and how the
similarities exist in doing that because
you're saying well i've built this and
now i have to work around it and i'm i'm
kind of in the same boat like i build
something and i'm like i've done
something a bit quirky there so i'm
gonna have to just deal with that
somehow and we'll we'll see how that
goes uh and it's exactly the same as as
you say with the sphere what's going on
here this looks like a city
am i right yeah so
so the idea behind my base was that i
would have the storage system in the
middle yeah originally when i started
work on it the plan was for it to be
like a
medium-sized storage system and then
things got out of hand which just
happens
yeah i think a creeper blew up oh no oh
that must just be a spot missing all
right i'll have to patch that up before
thanks grian now all of all of our
comments are going to be about that
whole eagle-eyed 3.4
i could spot a mistake a mile away
you know this this is a problem because
i've just realized while i was jumping
around as well that there's a window
missing from this build for some bizarre
reason so i'll point that one out before
you point that one out
um but yeah this this this city is kind
of going to be expanding out around the
storage system and it's going to consist
of
basically all the builds that i don't
want to be in that gigantic structure so
any farm that i construct is going to be
kind of out in this area floating above
the ocean um
for example this is my super smelter so
inside here you can see that we've got
all of the drops that are coming in from
my kelp farm they essentially flow into
these chests
which make their way up here
and then these furnaces smelt them and
then the dried kelp ends up in this
storage system over here which you have
to manually craft
yeah unfortunately there's no way to
automatically craft things in minecraft
just yet so yeah you have to manually
craft them and then you dump all of that
into that chest and then it all fills
into these furnaces so i kind of have
like a self
fuelling furnace system i'm going to and
this i'm going to need to use this okay
okay yeah yeah no no go ahead but yeah
so the plan for this this area is
basically all around the island
the the city is going to expand out and
it's going to have different buildings
of different shapes and sizes all kind
of similar in the way that they're built
like they're all kind of geometricy and
futuristic-y but then all around the
island we're going to have like this
this expanding city that's going to
sprawl out around it which is kind of
the plan you need to come up with your
vision of what you want and then i can
help you realize it
that would be amazing yeah that that
would be that would be a cool one and
that would be really really cool because
i've been sat here scratching my head so
much that i'm i'm going bald basically
that's that's been that's been the
experience of this hermitcraft season so
far is me staring very blankly at things
that i've built and being like i don't
really know what to do
but i did take down i did i don't know
if you saw my little my strange little
tower that i had going on with this
build that's now been removed so
it was a i built this very odd looking
tower and it was don't know if i saw it
i might have
i think you might have flown past i
think that
you
these could do with a bit more height on
them to make it look more city like yeah
that's that's the one thing as well is
that i was struggling with i kind of
want ver varied heights so i might
explain i might add another module to
this build on the right and then
that i wanted to do something to this
build and make it taller because the
original build was much taller than this
but nothing i did really felt
it just didn't it didn't feel that great
well maybe here's here's an idea for
this one in particular imagine here we
have
imagine these are like kelp
and we do like tubes of kelp like to the
height of it and then you sort of
decorate the kelp so you can tell what
the building is from a distance even if
these kelp don't actually do anything
themselves
yeah yeah yeah okay
that's not a bad idea just make it look
a little bit more substantial as well
there's also something else that's a
really easy fix
you're missing a contrast color
that's
yeah no you see i can't work i can't
work out what the contrast color would
be yeah hold on it's basically the same
as mine we're working with the same
palette here it's uh cyan cyan uh
terracotta
hold on let me let me go and grab some
and i'll show you exactly how this can
work yeah i think for example here you
want something
like this
it sounds like our first architect jobs
are actually going to be on our own
builds right yeah of course we need to
we need to sort ourselves out before we
show off to everyone else
yeah yeah yeah
oh that looks cool already something
like that
i i've only just built that on there but
you can see how it gives you a bit of
contrast into it oh for goodness sake
this is so frustrating you do you have
no you have no idea how how many hours i
spent
designing that structure
and then you come along and just
sprinkle some dark gray stuff on there
oh yeah it looks looks a million times
better the the key here is like there's
an anchor point so you can see like this
is now the middle of the base of this
building and then you can sort of
appreciate everything around it whereas
like at the moment because it's all
white you don't really know where to put
your eyes
yeah
oh yeah that looks so much better that
looks so cool
that looks wicked well i might have to i
might have to employ your services
to
just do do uh just the odd jobs in this
little area here yeah that will just
just just bring it together nothing too
crazy i'm not excited i'm not asking you
to spend hundreds of hours selling
anything just like this just trying to
add in bits to uh
um i'm not asking you to i mean
obviously if you feel like you need to
take down the entire structure then just
let me know and i'll pop mine and we can
we can tear it down together you nearly
never need to do that in minecraft you
can always make it work
all right well that's good to hear so
just anything any little details that
you think you could add to the build
that will will improve them and for
example like this one feel free to
expand it upwards um and feel free to do
anything
that you think is going to make it look
a little bit better because it's one of
those things i've i've struggled with
this for way too long and it's getting
to the point now where i don't want to
do any more episodes on it because i
feel bad for the viewers who keep seeing
me or something i'll be happy with it
i'm your next neighbor and i'm feeling
bad for you now
like i don't want to touch it ever again
i want to come back onto my base and
just be like oh look this is done like
and it looks great moving on
obviously while saying thank you to you
okay i think i can help you there did i
just hear death that'd be amazing i just
heard death
oh geez
have you seen how many kills zombie clio
has of phantoms by the way have you seen
how many cub has
how many does cub have like 250
no see zombie clio has 330 oh
i was insane i was going to
to try and compete i got like 40 and i
was like i'm doing well
yeah yeah i i i on the first day i got
seven and i was like this is great i'm
doing such a great job here and then
and then i went uh i went to boston or
italy or whatever and then i came back
and people were in the hundreds and i
was like well yeah never mind oh did you
see that shot
that was a pretty good shot i'll be
totally honest you i mean he was kind of
stuck no so i'll conduct three points
i don't know if i've i don't know if
i've got anything else to show you i
mean we've got the slime farm i've got
trust me i've been in the inner workings
of the slime farm i was gonna say yeah
you were very familiar with the slime
farm um but yeah other than that i mean
i i don't have i don't have too much
else to show you really other than just
i've i've seriously missed you from
being around because you've obviously
been away for a while and one of my
favorite things to do is to just appear
at your base do something random and
leave i know i've been so sporadically
like i've just been you know whenever
whenever i speak to people it's like oh
what you've got going on it's like i'm
going to boston in tomorrow and then
come back and it's like oh what you got
going on now so i'm leaving for italy in
the next couple days it's just been it's
been a manic a manic few months but for
now at least as far as i can tell i am
not leaving england for the rest of the
year so your friendly neighborhood egg
target should be poultry man strikes
again
i did say that's like the worst
superhero ever the superhero that no one
asked for
uh i did actually leave you a present at
the top of your egg if you didn't see it
yeah see i saw this actually as i flew
it as i was as i was jumping around my
base this morning
is this something that you want me to
crack on i'll be open i'll be i'll be
honest with you i didn't expect you to
fall for it
wait yeah well i expected it to explode
no you have to take out the bottom block
or you have to shoot them do you want to
do it at the same time
[Laughter]
they're like mercenaries it's like
watching like paratroopers dropping down
towards my face
cinnamon boys
that was like
the most ridiculous looking thing i've
ever seen in my life
i i thought they would just explode out
but they no minecraft doesn't work like
that anymore it used to but then you
have to cause some damage for them to
suddenly pop but what i hadn't expected
i wasn't expecting the bottom block i
wasn't expecting them to travel down
like a package of chicken
the most ridiculous thing oh my word my
stomach hurts from that one man
i feel sorry for headphone users because
both of us were just screeching
i'm so sorry
they've gone into the inner workings of
your redstone i'm sorry they're right
there they're never leaving i'm
constantly going to be hearing like when
i think they're all gone
i'm just gonna hear the the cluck and
i'll be like where is it
the last chicken it will never end
oh my goodness
that actually works out better than i
thought that was like a chicken firework
i think i think with the combined skills
we can actually make a really decent uh
area in this futuristic district and at
some point i feel like we can
create some sort of mechanism to combine
the two maybe oh yeah 100
and then this place would just become
magnificent and then ren is going to be
building a giant railway uh service so
like we could add a station in here i
could just yeah the future is bright for
the futuristic district
yeah i'm i'm super excited for it having
these two bases connected up and having
things going on between them especially
if we kind of have like a fairly uniform
color palette like what you've been
experimenting with
will really make things pop and you know
what now that i'm actually looking at
this
i'm very tempted to take out all of the
ice that i have going around here
and change it out with the dark clay it
might work yeah that might work i
i think that might look better because i
was looking at that today
well you're making me want to replace my
power beam this is the problem
but i'm not going to do that for the
time being because that took way too
long but
but no i think that the blocks around
the outside could actually do with some
of that so
we shall see we shall see we shall see
but anyway thank you ever so much for
popping by man yep and thank you for
showing me around and everything ah this
is cool so
i'll see you i guess when we start
working on the projects and stuff yeah
the super secret super species
yeah i don't i didn't even know what to
call it like the super secret secret
thing yeah we need it we need a name we
need a name code name yeah
i'll take suggestions on the secret name
even though you don't know what it is
yeah
yeah that's hilarious yeah commenters
please let us know down in the comment
section what you think we should call
the super secret project that you have
no idea about
yeah
all right
speak to you later see you later i've
already actually started doing a little
bit to mumbo's base based on what we
just did we actually had a really
productive meeting and we came up with
loads of plans i actually gave him a
tour of my base which will be on his
episode of hermitcraft and it should be
released about the same time so if you
want to go and see it go to his channel
and check it out as you can see i've
added some cyan terracotta here and it
has actually changed his base it's
neither for the better or for the worst
but it has changed it somewhat so i'd
like to see what he has to say about it
i've left him a little sign
saying that i've like done a little
taster and i want to get his opinion on
it so this is here did a sample with
cyan terra on the quarter of the sphere
let me know what you think g
so
we will find out exactly how that's
going to go later on i don't want to do
too much work in case he doesn't like it
but this is a pretty good place to start
i feel
so that's it for today's episode of
hermitcraft it was a little bit
different today not what we're used to
perhaps but for now i think i'm going to
start
on my secret project
i'll see you guys in the next episode